Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：是的，是的，队长。
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:  : Aye, aye,
Captain.
孩子们: : 是啊是啊
队长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the
deck and flop like a fish ♪
队长：♪ 那么就降落在
像鱼一样翻牌和翻牌♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
SpongeBob:
May I help you, sir?
海绵宝宝：
先生，我可以帮你吗？
I'd like  that  table
by the window.
我想要那张桌子
靠窗。
As soon as the present
customers are done with it.
只要现在
客户已经完成了。
They like to chew their
food thoroughly.
他们喜欢咀嚼自己的
食物彻底。
97, 98, 99...
97、98、99……
Don't rush me, woman!
别催我，女人！
Perhaps this will
speed up the process.
也许这会
加快进程。
How will that help
them chew faster?
这有什么帮助
他们咀嚼得更快？
SpongeBob, what's
the problem?
海绵宝宝，什么
问题是什么？
No problem, I was just
telling this customer
没问题，我只是
告诉这位顾客
he has to wait for his
favorite table.
他必须等待他的
最喜欢的桌子。
Five bucks if I get
the table now.
如果我得到的话五块钱
现在的桌子。
Ah...!
啊...！
Oh, my hip.
哦，我的臀部。
Enjoy your meal.
请享用。
Let me know if you
need anything else.
让我知道如果你
还需要什么东西。
Why did you give
him the table?
你为什么给
他那桌？
You know what they say:
"money talks".
你知道他们怎么说：
“金钱万能”。
I didn't know
money could talk.
我不知道
钱可以说话。
Did it tell you to kick
those old people out?
它告诉你踢吗
那些老人出去了？
What do you have
against old people?
你有什么
反对老人？
Don't go goofy
on me, boy.
别傻了
在我身上，男孩。
Money can't really talk.
钱真的不能说话。
Only fish can talk.
只有鱼会说话。
Wouldn't it be neat
if money could talk?
岂不是很整齐
如果钱会说话？
Yeah.
是的。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
What's that music?
那是什么音乐？
I think Mr. Krabs
is gonna sing.
我认为蟹老板
会唱歌。
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
♪ If I could talk to money ♪
♪ 如果我能和钱说话 ♪
♪ How great my life would be ♪
♪ 我的生活将会多么美好 ♪
♪ We'd tell
each other secrets ♪
♪ 我们会告诉
彼此的秘密♪
♪ All their friends
would visit me ♪
♪ 他们所有的朋友
会来看我♪
♪ I'd bathe in filthy riches ♪
♪ 我会沐浴在肮脏的财富中 ♪
♪ Which is clean
enough for me ♪
♪ 哪个是干净的
对我来说足够了♪
♪ Oh, if you could tell
me what you want ♪
♪ 哦，如果你能告诉的话
我你想要什么♪
♪ How happy we would be ♪
♪ 我们会多么幸福 ♪
♪ We'd surely
be the best of friends ♪
♪ 我们肯定会
成为最好的朋友♪
♪ We'd never disagree ♪
♪ 我们永远不会有分歧 ♪
♪ There couldn't be
a downside ♪
♪ 不可能有
缺点♪
♪ Not one that I could see ♪
♪ 我看不见的人 ♪
♪ If I could talk to money ♪
♪ 如果我能和钱说话 ♪
♪ Come along, sing with me ♪
♪ 来和我一起唱歌 ♪
Uh, no thanks,
I got to go.
呃，不用了，谢谢，
我得走了。
I really have to pee.
我真的要尿尿。
♪ If I could talk to money ♪
♪ 如果我能和钱说话 ♪
♪ And it could talk to me... ♪
♪ 它可以跟我说话...... ♪
♪ We'd always
be the best of friends ♪
♪ 我们总是
成为最好的朋友♪
♪ For all eternity ♪
♪ 永远 ♪
What did I miss?
我错过了什么？
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ If I could talk to money ♪
♪ 如果我能和钱说话 ♪
♪ How great my life... ♪
♪ 我的生活多么美好...♪
Parlez vous Francais?
Parlez vous 法国人？
Hable espanol?
哈布尔西班牙语？
Oo-yay eak-spay
ig-pay atin-lay?
哦耶 eak-spay
ig-pay atin-lay？
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
Maybe this will make you talk.
也许这会让你说话。
Talk!
讲话！
You're bein' too hard
on the little guy.
你太难了
在小家伙身上。
You can talk to me.
你可以和我谈谈。
I'm your friend.
我是你的朋友。
I would give anything
to talk to money.
我愿意付出一切
与金钱交谈。
Anything!
任何事物！
Anything?
任何事物？
You?
你？
That's right.
这是正确的。
'Tis I, the ominous
Flying Dutchman.
这就是我，不祥的
飞翔的荷兰人.
I'll grant your wish.
我会满足你的愿望。
But it'll cost you.
但这会让你付出代价。
Yeah, yeah, my
immortal soul.
是啊是啊我的
不朽的灵魂。
I've heard
that speech before.
我听说过
之前那个演讲。
Wha...?
世界卫生大会...？
Well, uh, great.
嗯，太好了。
But be warned!
但请注意！
Yeah, yeah, skip
the lecture.
是啊是啊，跳过
讲座。
I want what's
coming to me.
我想要什么
来找我。
Humph, you're no fun
at all, you know that?
哼，你不好玩
无论如何，你知道吗？
Hey, is that pixie dust?
嘿，那是仙尘吗？
Uh, uh.
呃，呃。
Ooh, that was a strange dream.
哦，那是一个奇怪的梦。
Male voice: You think that was
a strange dream?
男声：你以为那是
一个奇怪的梦？
I dreamt I was trapped in a
prison made of peanut butter.
我梦见自己被困在一个
用花生酱做的监狱。
Who said that?
谁说的？
Hey, it's a nickel.
嘿，这是一个五分钱。
What were you doing in my belly
button, little fella?
你在我肚子里做什么
按钮，小家伙？
I got stuck in there during
your last coin shower.
期间我被困在那里
你最后一次投币淋浴。
I don't want
to talk about it.
我不想要
谈论它。
Do  you  have anything
to say to me?
你有什么吗
对我说？
Yeah, when's the last
time you brushed your teeth?
是的，最后一次是什么时候
你什么时候刷牙？
Oh, it worked.
哦，成功了。
I can talk to money.
我可以和钱说话。
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
Please, don't start
singing again.
请不要开始
再次唱歌。
Don't worry, darlings.
别担心，亲爱的。
Soon you'll be rejoined
with all your friends.
很快你就会重新加入
和你所有的朋友。
Oh, my, why don't you
kiss me like that?
哦，我的天，你为什么不呢？
就这样吻我吗？
Don't start.
不要开始。
That'll be $5.
那将是 5 美元。
Hey, dudes.
嘿，伙计们。
Run, jump!
跑、跳！
Jump out, jump out!
跳出来，跳出来！
Good morning, my darlings.
早上好，亲爱的。
Money: Good morning, Mr. Krabs.
Money：早上好，蟹老板。
You're coming home with me.
你要和我一起回家。
Money: Yay!
钱：耶！
SpongeBob, I did it.
海绵宝宝，我做到了。
I can talk to money.
我可以和钱说话。
Go ahead, say hello.
来吧，打个招呼。
Hello... money.
你好……钱。
Oh, aren't they a riot?
哦，他们不是骚乱吗？
I'm really starting
to worry about Mr. Krabs.
我真的开始了
担心蟹老板。
I'm worried he just
left with my paycheck.
我担心他只是
留下了我的薪水。
Now that we're alone, let's
tell each other secrets.
既然我们都孤单了，那就让我们
告诉彼此秘密。
What kind of secrets
are you talking about?
什么样的秘密
你在说什么？
Yeah, we live
in a safe.
是的，我们住
在保险箱里。
You got any friends you
could invite over?
你有朋友吗
可以邀请过来吗？
Aren't we enough for you?
我们还不够你吗？
What's wrong with us?
我们怎么了？
Money: Yeah!
钱：是啊！
Nothing, nothing,
you guys are great.
没什么，没什么，
你们太棒了。
I thought you guys might
want some company
我以为你们可能
想要有人陪伴
you know, to make
you happy.
你知道，为了使
你快乐。
Money: Why don't you ask what
would make us happy?
钱：你为什么不问什么
会让我们快乐吗？
OK, so how can
I make you happy?
好吧，那怎么办
我让你幸福吗？
Money: Spend us.
钱：花我们。
We're money.
我们是钱。
It's in our nature.
这是我们的本性。
I've been trapped in that safe
for eight years.
我被困在那个保险箱里
八年了。
I always wanted to be spent
on a fairy princess outfit.
我一直想被花掉
穿着仙女公主装。
What? No way.
什么？决不。
I want to be
spent on corn dogs.
我想成为
花在玉米热狗上。
I want to be spent
on diapers.
我想被花掉
在尿布上。
Money: Yeah, yeah, me too.
钱：是啊是啊，我也是。
Oh, wait a minute.
哦，等一下。
I am not spending you
on corn dogs, diapers
我不花钱你
在玉米热狗、尿布上
or fairy princess outfits.
或童话公主服装。
Woman: Did you
find everything OK?
女：你有吗
发现一切正常吗？
Unfortunately.
很遗憾。
Money: Yeah, all right.
钱：是啊，好吧。
Mr. Krabs,
lookin' good.
蟹老板先生，
看起来不错。
What's wrong
with Mr. Krabs?
怎么了
和蟹老板一起？
I don't know.
我不知道。
He's acting
kind of weird.
他在演戏
有点奇怪。
Money:  :
Spend us.
钱: :
花我们吧
Spend us.
I can't spend all of you.
我不能花掉你们的全部。
And none of you want
to be spent on stuff I want.
你们谁也不想要
花在我想要的东西上。
Money: Spend us.
钱：花我们。
Ah, you're all shallow
and self-absorbed.
啊，你们都是浅薄的
和自我陶醉。
What did I ever see in you?
我在你身上看到了什么？
Money: Spend us.
钱：花我们。
I'm not listening.
我不听。
Money: Spend us.
钱：花我们。
I'm not...
我不是...
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Hi, Mr. Krabs.
嗨，蟹老板。
I just came by to make
sure you weren't
我只是过来做
当然你不是
you know, totally insane.
你知道，完全疯了。
Take this bag as far away
as possible and bury it.
带着这个包走得尽可能远
尽可能地把它埋起来。
Ooh, ooh-
what have I done?
噢噢——
我做了什么？
Give me that back.
把那个还给我。
OK, glad you're
not insane.
好的，很高兴你
没疯。
Dutchman,
you cheated me.
荷兰人,
你欺骗了我。
Take this horrible curse away.
把这个可怕的诅咒拿走吧。
I want a refund.
我想要退款。
All sales are final
from the Flying Dutchman
所有销售都是最终的
来自飞翔的荷兰人号
especially for a selfish
shellfish like yourself.
尤其对于一个自私的人来说
像你一样的贝类。
Try saying that three
times fast.
试着说三
倍快。
Your soul's going in
me fanny pack of despair.
你的灵魂要进去
我绝望的腰包。
Now pay up.
现在付钱吧。
Huh?
啊？
An I.O.U.?
欠条？
Hee-hee, yeah, well, I sort of
sold my soul already.
嘻嘻，是啊，我有点
已经出卖了我的灵魂。
What? To who?
什么？给谁？
Those guys.
那些家伙。
We were here
first, Pops.
我们在这里
首先，波普斯。
We've all got a claim
on Krabs' soul.
我们都有索赔
蟹蟹的灵魂。
Get to the back
of the line.
到后面去
的线。
Now, now, I'm sure we
can sort this out.
现在，现在，我确信我们
可以解决这个问题。
You too, SpongeBob?
你也是吗，海绵宝宝？
He was $5
short on payday.
他当时是5美元
发薪日短缺。
Narrator:  Ahoy, mateys.
旁白：嘿，伙计们。
Today I'll be spinning a tale
you won't soon forget.
今天我要编一个故事
你不会很快忘记的。
It's called SpongeBob
SquarePants vs. The Patty
Gadget.
它的名字叫海绵宝宝
方裤 vs 帕蒂
小工具。
Now SpongeBob was working.
现在海绵宝宝正在工作。
his eye on the grill
他的眼睛盯着烤架
till he heard a sharp sound
that gave him a chill.
直到他听到一声尖锐的声音
这让他不寒而栗。
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
What could it mean?
这意味着什么？
Wow, it's a deep-fry patty
cookin' machine.
哇，这是炸肉饼
烹饪机。
And hiding behind it,
who do we see?
并躲在它的背后，
我们看到谁？
None other than Squidward
不是别人，正是章鱼哥
and his bad face acne.
还有他那张糟糕的脸上的痘痘。
What is this contraption you've
hauled into me place?
你的这个装置是什么？
拖到我的地方？
A miracle, a marvel.
一个奇迹，一个奇迹。
It will cook Krabby Patties
at a fabulous pace.
它会煮蟹肉饼
以惊人的速度。
But how are
the patties?
但怎么样
肉饼？
I mean, how do they taste?
我的意思是，它们味道如何？
I'll let you try one.
我会让你尝试一个。
Shove this in your face.
把这个推到你脸上。
I have to admit that patty
was yummy.
我不得不承认帕蒂
很好吃。
Though it sits like a rock
when it lands in me tummy.
虽然它像岩石一样坐着
当它落在我肚子里的时候。
But I've got me a fry cook
但我有一个炒菜厨师
and he's always on time.
他总是准时。
Ah, but this gizmo is faster
啊，但是这个小玩意更快
and you won't pay it a dime.
而且你不会付一毛钱。
Your machine sounds
delightful
你的机器发出声音
令人愉快的
but how much does it cost?
但要花多少钱？
Hmm, just fire SpongeBob
嗯，就解雇海绵宝宝吧
and tell him get lost.
并告诉他滚开。
The machine wanted his
job to make SpongeBob quit
机器想要他的
让海绵宝宝退出的工作
and SpongeBob didn't like it.
海绵宝宝不喜欢它。
No, not one bit.
不，一点也没有。
Pushing his grill, SpongeBob
burst through the door.
海绵宝宝推着他的烤架
破门而入。
I challenge your gadget.
我挑战你的小工具。
I declare patty war.
我向帕蒂宣战。
With three little words,
Krabs started the show.
简单的三个字，
螃蟹开始表演。
Flag raised in the air,
he cried
旗帜在空中升起，
他哭了
ready, set, go...!
准备好，出发，出发……！
Quick as a flash, Squidward
pulled the big lever.
快如闪电，章鱼哥
拉动大杠杆。
Then sat back and watched,
feeling, oh, so quite clever.
然后坐下来观看，
感觉哦，真是太聪明了。
SpongeBob with spatula
held tight in his fist,
海绵宝宝用抹刀
紧紧握在拳头里，
flung 20 patties,
not a single one missed.
扔20个肉饼，
没有一个错过。
The crowd was impressed.
众人印象深刻。
Wow!
哇！
They cheered full of glee.
他们欢呼雀跃。
All except Patrick,
who had to go pee.
除了帕特里克之外，所有人
谁必须去撒尿。
A noise and a clatter
came from the machine.
一阵噪音和咔嗒声
来自机器。
And out popped the patties
in a burst of hot steam.
然后肉饼就出来了
一阵热气中。
The gadget was fast.
这个小工具速度很快。
Its first batch completed.
第一批已完成。
But SpongeBob yelled out
但海绵宝宝大声喊道
"I won't be defeated"!
“我不会被打败”！
He took in some air.
他吸了一口气。
SpongeBob swelled his physique.
海绵宝宝的体格膨胀了。
Then dozens of patties filled
up his cheeks.
然后填了几十个肉饼
抬起他的脸颊。
He strained and he sweated.
他使劲用力，出了汗。
He summoned his will.
他召唤出了自己的意志。
And shot Krabby Patties,
right onto the grill.
并拍摄了蟹肉饼，
就在烤架上。
"Not bad"
“不错”
Yelled out Squidward.
章鱼哥大声喊道。
A really good try.
真是一次很好的尝试。
But let's see how you do
against my machine
set on high.
但让我们看看你怎么做
针对我的机器
设置为高。
The gizmo, it shuddered.
这个小玩意，它颤抖着。
It clattered, it shook.
它叮当响，它摇晃。
And as Squidward laughed:
章鱼哥大笑道：
Sandy said:
桑迪说：
But ol' SpongeBob cried out
但海绵宝宝却大喊大叫
"I won't lose to that thing"!
“我不会输给那个东西的”！
Then he raised up two
spatulas
然后他举起了两个
铲子
and leapt like a spring.
并像弹簧一样跳跃。
His hands were a blur,
the patties went flying.
他的手已经模糊了
肉饼飞了起来。
He fried up a hundred
without even trying.
他炒了一百个
甚至没有尝试。
Squidward was worried,
SpongeBob couldn't be beat.
章鱼哥很担心，
海绵宝宝是无法被击败的。
I got one last chance,
I'll turn up the heat.
我还有最后一次机会
我会把暖气调高。
He struggled and strained
他挣扎着、紧张着
till his face turned dark blue.
直到他的脸变成深蓝色。
Then the lever moved forward
然后杠杆向前移动
and broke right in two.
并断成两半。
The gadget buckled and sparked.
这个小玩意弯曲并冒出火花。
It cracked like a gun.
它像枪一样破裂。
So Squidward took off
yelling
于是章鱼哥就起飞了
大喊大叫
"Let me know if I've won".
“如果我赢了请告诉我”。
Lightning flew from its maw.
闪电从它的肚子里飞了出来。
It looked ready to burst.
它看起来快要爆炸了。
But SpongeBob, still
standing, yelled
但海绵宝宝，依然
站着，大喊
"foul beast, do your worst".
“邪恶的野兽，尽你所能”。
The patties came flying
by twos and by threes.
肉饼飞来了
三三两两。
By dozens, by hundreds,
oh, it was something to see.
数十个、数百个，
哦，这是值得一看的东西。
Aye, that machine, it was fast.
是的，那台机器，速度很快。
But SpongeBob was faster.
但海绵宝宝更快。
He'd prove to that thing
that he was its master.
他会证明那件事
他是它的主人。
The gadget blew into bits
and died with a boom.
这个小工具被炸成了碎片
并轰然死去。
The blast was so loud
爆炸声是如此之大
it woke King Neptune.
它唤醒了海王星国王。
: What's that?
: 那是什么？
It was all over,
finished and done.
一切都结束了，
完成并完成。
With his head
held up high
用他的头
高举
SpongeBob knew he had won.
海绵宝宝知道他赢了。
The crowd yelled, "hooray
众人高呼：“万岁
Squidward's name is now mud"!
章鱼哥的名字现在是泥”！
But as they were cheering
但正当他们欢呼雀跃时
SpongeBob fell with a thud.
海绵宝宝重重地摔倒了。
SpongeBob: Unh.
海绵宝宝：呃。
The service was short.
服务时间很短。
Tears shed with regret.
流下遗憾的泪水。
Squidward, it seemed, was
the one most upset.
章鱼哥，看起来，是
最心烦意乱的人。
Whoo, yeah!
呼，是啊！
What's that?
那是什么？
You thought SpongeBob was
buried down there?
你以为海绵宝宝是
埋在那里？
They just buried the gadget
他们刚刚埋了这个小玩意
Ha-ha, this I swear.
哈哈，我发誓。
Well, that ends me tale,
straight from the book.
好吧，我的故事到此结束，
直接从书中。
Now I got to go
and polish me hook.
现在我得走了
并擦亮我的钩子。
Well, Squidward, ol' boy
嗯，章鱼哥，老男孩
all that's left is to go win
that dancing trophy
剩下的就是去赢
那个跳舞奖杯
and give it a home.
并给它一个家。
After all, nobody ever worked
harder to get it than you.
毕竟没人工作过
比你更难得到它。
All those years of training
with the masters.
这么多年的训练
与大师们。
Your tireless effort to keep
your instrument supple.
你孜孜不倦的努力保持着
你的乐器柔软。
Not to mention your weekly
thigh waxing.
更不用说你的每周
大腿打蜡。
And now it's time
to go get it.
现在是时候了
去拿它。
So, let's do it.
那么，让我们开始吧。
Whoo...!
呼...！
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
啧，啧，啧，啧。
Want to give me a ruling,
SpongeBob?
想要给我一个裁决，
海绵宝宝？
Sorry, Squidward,
you got to go lower to win.
对不起，章鱼哥，
你必须降低才能获胜。
What?
什么？
What are you two doing?
你们两个在做什么？
We're limbo dancing
我们在地狱之舞
to get ready for the
dance-a-thon auditions.
为
舞蹈马拉松试镜。
We're gonna win the trophy.
我们会赢得奖杯。
Ha, the two of you?
哈，你们两个？
Don't make me laugh.
别让我笑。
Come here...
See that?
来这里...
看到了吗？
That's where
the trophy's going.
那就是那里
奖杯就要出发了。
Ooh...
哦...
You built us a trophy case
for when we win?
你为我们打造了一个奖杯柜
我们什么时候赢？
Oh, you are a true friend.
哦，你是一个真正的朋友。
No, you twits.
不，你们这些笨蛋。
I built that trophy case
for me when  I  win.
我建造了那个奖杯柜
当我获胜时对我来说。
I'm going to ace
the tryouts today
我要成为王牌
今天的选拔赛
and then I'm going
to the finals tomorrow
然后我要去
到明天的决赛
and win the trophy.
并赢得奖杯。
I am going forth to meet
my destiny.
我要出去迎接
我的命运。
Good-bye.
再见。
Ruling, SpongeBob?
裁决，海绵宝宝？
I think we better
raise the bar.
我认为我们更好
提高标准。
Hiya, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
The Flying Gavonne Brothers.
飞翔的加冯兄弟。
Just ignore them, Squidward.
别理他们，章鱼哥。
Female:  :
Contestants 51 and 52
to the stage, please.
女: :
参赛者51和52
请上台。
We're up, Patrick.
我们起来了，帕特里克。
Wish us luck, Squidward.
祝我们好运，章鱼哥。
Do I know you?
我知道你？
You kidder.
你个小鬼。
Let's go, Patrick.
我们走吧，帕特里克。
Poor boobs, they don't
stand a chance.
可怜的胸部，他们没有
有机会。
Yell, see you at the finals,
Squidward.
呐喊，决赛见
章鱼哥。
You actually got in?
你真的进去了？
Yep.
是的。
Humph, if those two
nitwits made it
哼，如果那两个
白痴做到了
then I'm a shoo-in.
那我就稳操胜券了。
Female:  :
Contestant 53 to the stage,
please.
女: :
53号选手上台，
请。
Look out, dancing world
小心，舞蹈的世界
here comes your future.
你的未来来了。
Music, please.
请听音乐。
Male Judge: Next.
男评委：下一位。
Excuse me?
打扰一下？
You're done.
你完成了。
You know, next contestant.
你知道，下一位参赛者。
You didn't make the cut,
sorry, Mac.
你没有晋级，
对不起，麦克。
But, but, but, but,
you don't understand.
但是，但是，但是，但是，
你不明白。
I, I, I already built
a trophy case
我我我已经建好了
奖杯箱
with the cutest little plaque.
带着最可爱的小牌匾。
If I could just, just,
just touch it.
如果我可以，只是，
只需触摸它即可。
Squidward: But I, hey...
章鱼哥：但是我，嘿……
Unhand me, you brutes.
放开我，你们这些畜生。
Ah!
啊!
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
You're just not getting
into the spirit of this
thing, Squidward.
你只是没有得到
本着这个精神
事情，章鱼哥。
Doh, help me up.
呵呵，扶我起来吧。
How'd the audition go,
Squidward?
试镜怎么样，
章鱼哥？
The audition?
试镜？
My trophy?
我的奖杯？
I mean, uh, uh...
我的意思是，呃，呃……
Yeah, the audition.
是的，试镜。
Evidently,
I'm such a great dancer
显然，
我是一个很棒的舞者
that I've been banned from
the competition for life.
我被禁止了
生命的竞争。
Whoa.
哇哦。
Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
Would you be our coach
for the finals?
你愿意当我们的教练吗
为了决赛？
What?
什么？
I've got better things to do
than help you two dopes.
我还有更重要的事情要做
还不如帮助你们两个笨蛋。
Like polishing your empty
trophy case?
就像擦亮你的空虚
奖杯盒？
Fine.
美好的。
But I keep the trophy
when we win, deal?
但奖杯我保留着
当我们赢了，交易？
Deal.
交易。
OK.
好的。
Show me what you
got, Patrick.
让我看看你是什么
得到了，帕特里克。
OK, here I go.
好的，我开始了。
Watch me now.
现在看着我。
Ooh, cramp!
噢，抽筋了！
Well, I guess that
just leaves you, SpongeBob.
嗯，我想是这样
就离开你了，海绵宝宝。
Show me your stuff.
给我看看你的东西。
Ready, and...
准备好了，然后...
Having fun?
玩得开心吗？
Yes, yes, I am.
是的，是的，我是。
SpongeBob, dancing isn't
supposed to be fun.
海绵宝宝，跳舞不是
应该很有趣。
It's supposed to be art
应该是艺术
and art is suffering!
而艺术就是受苦！
Now, we'll start
with some ballet.
现在，我们开始
一些芭蕾舞。
Watch my feet
and follow my lead.
注意我的脚
并跟随我的带领。
Ready, and plie.
准备好了，开始吧。
Releve.
释放。
And now, grand jete-
现在，大喷气机-
ahh...
啊...
Oh, where am I?
噢，我在哪儿？
See if I can find the lights.
看看能不能找到灯。
Ah...!
啊...！
Squidward: Wait a minute.
章鱼哥：等一下。
Oh!
哦！
Squidward: This gives
me an idea.
章鱼哥：这给了
我有一个想法。
Ready, SpongeBob?
准备好了吗，海绵宝宝？
Ready.
准备好。
A one and a two, and plie.
一个一，一个二，还有层。
Jete.
杰特。
Releve.
释放。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
This will
never work.
这将
从来不工作。
You've got two left feet.
你有两只左脚。
SpongeBob: How'd you know?
海绵宝宝：你怎么知道？
Squidward: Give me those.
章鱼哥：把那些给我。
Unh...
呃……
That's better.
这样更好。
OK, let's go.
好的，我们走吧。
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
海绵宝宝，你在做什么？
Why are you moving your
arms like that?
你为什么要移动你的
手臂就这样？
I guess
they're happy.
我猜
他们很高兴。
Squidward: Argh, hand 'em over.
章鱼哥：啊，把它们交出来。
And the other one, come on.
另一位，来吧。
Unh...
呃……
Now, that's
more like it.
现在，那就是
更喜欢它。
Gee, Squidward, with your arms
and legs doing all the work
哎呀，章鱼哥，用你的手臂
和腿做所有的工作
I'm not really doing anything.
我其实什么也没做。
I think I should help.
我想我应该帮忙。
Are you questioning
my leadership?
你在质疑吗
我的领导？
Well, I just...
嗯，我只是...
OK, hand it over.
好的，交给吧。
You know what, Squidward?
你知道吗，章鱼哥？
What?
什么？
I think I'm suffering
for my art now.
我想我很痛苦
现在为了我的艺术。
Good gravy.
好肉汁。
Get a load of the talent here.
在这里获得大量人才。
Oh, please.
哦，拜托。
Just wait until you see my
brilliant moves.
等你看到我的
精彩的动作。
Ooh.
哦。
Oh...
哦...
Oh my goodness.
哦，我的天啊。
I am honored to be in the
presence of such divine talent.
我很荣幸能够在
有如此神圣天赋的存在。
Quit groveling.
别再卑躬屈膝了。
Where
is your dignity?
哪里
你的尊严是什么？
These losers are here
to worship us.
这些失败者都在这里
来崇拜我们。
I mean me.
我是说我。
By the end of the night
到了晚上结束的时候
I'll have them
on their knees
我会拥有它们
跪下
just begging for more.
只是乞求更多。
Female:  : Now
that's what I like to call
女: : 现在
这就是我喜欢称呼的
a hard act to follow.
这是一个很难遵循的行为。
Next up, we have SpongeBob
SquarePants.
接下来，我们有海绵宝宝
方裤。
Oh, man.
哦，伙计。
I can't wait.
我等不及了。
I am  so  stoked
on dancing right now.
我很兴奋
现在就跳舞。
Now before I begin
在我开始之前
let me just thank you all for
coming out tonight.
让我感谢你们所有人
今晚出来。
Will you please stop it?
请你停下来好吗？
And let my dancing
do the talking.
让我的舞蹈
说话。
Wow, Squidward, the crowd's
gone silent.
哇，章鱼哥，人群的
沉默了。
Of course they have.
当然有。
They are in the presence
of a true artiste.
他们在场
一个真正的艺术家。
What's he doing?
他在做什么？
Is he hurt?
他受伤了吗？
I don't know, man, but
it's hurting my eyes.
我不知道，伙计，但是
它伤害了我的眼睛。
I think I'm gonna be sick.
我想我会生病。
Uh, Squidward?
呃，章鱼哥？
Ha, if they think that's good
哈，如果他们认为这样很好的话
wait till they see...
等到他们看到...
Cramp!
抽筋！
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！
Huh?
啊？
Hey, guys, wait up.
嘿，伙计们，等等。
Huh? What's this?
啊？这是什么？
That's kind of nice.
这很好。
Hey guys, come check this out.
嘿伙计们，快来看看这个吧。
Must finish dance...
On other...
一定要跳完舞...
在其他...
Um, Squidward,
is this part of the act?
嗯，章鱼哥，
这是该法案的一部分吗？
The pain!
痛苦！
By unanimous decision,
we have a winner.
经一致决定，
我们有一个胜利者。
Mine!
矿！
I won, I won!
我赢了，我赢了！
Never before have
I seen such zest
以前从未有过
我看到了这样的热情
such  joie de vivre.
这样的生活乐趣。
Oh, thank you,
you're too kind.
哦，谢谢你，
你太善良了。
But I couldn't have done it
without a very special someone.
但我做不到
没有一个非常特别的人。
Wait, SpongeBob, no!
等等，海绵宝宝，不！
The rulebook clearly states
规则手册明确规定
"A single dancer must
perform
“一个舞者必须
执行
without any further assistance
from a partner."
没有任何进一步的帮助
来自合作伙伴。”
Therefore, you're the winner.
因此，你是赢家。
Oh man, the jig's up, Pedro.
噢，伙计，一切都准备好了，佩德罗。
We're goin' home.
我们要回家了
It's all right,
I'll go call a taxi.
没关系，
我去叫出租车。
Merciful Neptune.
仁慈的海王星。
Are there any more cheaters?
难道还有更多骗子吗？
Oh, crud, we're two dancers.
哦，天哪，我们是两个舞者。
We're nine dancers actually.
实际上我们是九个舞者。
Does this count?
这算不算？
Isn't there
a single dancer here
没有吗
这里有一个舞者
who is not assisted
by a partner?
谁没有得到帮助
由合作伙伴？
Uh, what about number 52
over there?
呃，52号呢
在那儿？
Is he alone?
他一个人吗？
Patrick:
帕特里克：
Why, yes,
he is a single dancer.
为什么，是的，
他是一名单身舞者。
Oh, well, then.
哦，那么好吧。
I guess he wins.
我猜他赢了。
I love your new
dance, Patrick.
我喜欢你的新
跳舞吧，帕特里克。
French Narrator: Epilogue.
法语旁白：尾声。
Woman: Tommy?
女：汤米？
I've got a fresh load
of laundr...
我有新的负载
洗衣房的...
Tommy, oh, oh, dear me, no!
汤米，哦，哦，天哪，不！
Hello, it's an emergency.
你好，情况紧急。
My son! He's...
我的儿子！他是...
Mom, calm down.
妈妈，冷静点。
I'm just doing
"The Cramp"!
我只是在做
“抽筋”！
Oh... Oh, you kids
哦...哦，你们这些孩子
and your crazy dance fads.
还有你疯狂的舞蹈时尚。
Hey, everybody.
嘿，大家。
Let's all do "The Cramp"!
大家一起来做“抽筋”吧！
Yeah!
是的！